[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：生成器是ES6中引入的一种新的奇异形式的函数。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: A generator is a new exotic form of function introduced in ES6.
我们先来看看实际的机制，
And we're going to look at the actual mechanism first,
了解它的一些工作原理和诸如此类的事情。
understanding some of how it works and that kind of thing.
一开始当我们看到它的时候，它不会
And at first as we're looking at it, it's not gonna
看起来这与异步编程有任何关系。
look like this has anything at all to do with asynchronous programming.
这看起来会有点奇怪和不合时宜。
It's going to seem a bit strange and out of place.
我保证我们经历这一切是有原因的。
I promise there's a reason why we're going through it.
这是整个图景的基本部分。
This is a fundamental part of the whole picture.
如果承诺是关于解决回调中的控制反转问题
If promises were about solving the inversion of control issue in callback
见鬼，发电机是用来解决非本地的，
hell, generators are about solving the non-local,
非顺序合理性问题。
non-sequential reasonability problem.
所以他们会为我们提供一个非常强大的模式。
So they are gonna provide us a really powerful pattern for that.
但我们需要理解，我们需要穿过管道
But we need to understand, we need to kinda walk through the plumbing of
来了解它是如何工作的。
the stuff to understand how it's working.
你可能从来没有意识到的一件事
One of the things that you may not have ever realized about
你对JavaScript的假设。
your assumptions with JavaScript.
所有的函数，所有的正常函数都有它们的特征
Is that all functions, all normal functions have a characteristic of them
其奇特的说法是，它们具有run-to-complete语义。
which the fancy way of saying it is that they have a run-to-completion semantic.
这意味着当函数开始运行时，
What that means is that when a function starts running,
它将始终运行到该函数的末尾，并且
it will always run to the end of that function and
在任何其他功能有机会进入并开始运行之前完成。
finish before any other function has an opportunity to come in and start running.
在任何给定的时刻，只有一个函数在积极执行。
At any given moment, only one function is actively executing.
这并不意味着它不能调用其他函数。
And that doesn't mean it can't call to other functions.
但这意味着没有人可以进来
But it means that nobody can come in and
预先中断此函数以运行其他功能。
pre-emptively interrupt this function to run something else.
它是Run-to-Complete语义。
It's a run-to-completion semantic.
这在本质上可能看起来很学术性，但是
And that may seem very academic in nature, but
这实际上是JavaScript最重要的特征之一。
it's actually one of the most important characteristics of JavaScript.
它允许我们以单线程的方式对事物进行推理。
It's what allows us to reason about things in a single threaded fashion.
不用担心两个功能，一个中断另一个
Never having to worry about two functions, one interrupting the other one and
以我们无法理解的方式破坏我们的共享记忆。
corrupting our shared memory in ways that we don't understand.
在线程编程中必须处理的所有问题都得到了
All the problems that you have to deal with in threaded programming get
当你没有Run-to-Complete语义时引入，好吗？
introduced when you don't have that run-to-completion semantic, okay?
所以这是我们建造的最基本的东西之一
So it's one of the most fundamental things that we've built all of
我们对JavaScript的理解结束了。
our understanding on JavaScript over.
所以当我告诉你发电机时，可能会在这里引起一些警告
So that might raise a few warning flags in here when I tell you generators
没有Run-to-Complete语义。
do not have a run-to-completion semantic.
它们是一种完全不同的功能。
They're a different kind of function altogether.
这是一种非常不同的野兽。
It's a very different kind of beast.
现在，这并不是为了在你的程序中引入混乱而设计的。
Now that's not designed to introduce chaos into your program.
它的设计目的是引入一种行为，我们
It's designed to introduce a behavior that we
以前不得不去做大量的工作来模拟。
previously had to go to a lot of work to simulate.
所以，如果你愿意，它在我们的行为之上添加了一种句法糖分
So it's adding a syntactic sugar, if you will, on top of a behavior that we would
不得不花费相当多的时间和精力去尝试模仿，好吗？
have had to spend quite a bit of time and effort to try to emulate, okay?
所以，我们尝试用生成器的语法创建的东西，
So, the thing that we are attempting to create with the syntax of a generator,
顺便说一下，JavaScript没有发明生成器，
by the way JavaScript didn't invent generators,
它们来自其他语言，如Python。
they come from other languages like Python.
但是我们试图用JavaScript生成器创建的东西，
But the thing that we're trying to create with the JavaScript generator,
是声明状态机的语法形式。
is a syntactic form of declaring a state machine.
对于那些没有意识到的人来说，状态机是一种具有模式的方式
State machines are, for those of you that aren't aware, a way of having a patterned
从一种状态到另一种状态的一系列流动。
series of flow from one state to another state to another state.
并声明性地列出所有那些状态和那些转换输出。
And declaratively listing all those states and those transitions out.
所以我们可以在没有生成器的情况下实现状态机。
So we can implement state machines without generators.
我已经做过很多次了。
And I've done that many times.
你们中的一些人可能已经实现了自己的状态机。
Some of you may have implemented your own state machines.
但是你必须去做大量的工作，而且你最终不得不使用闭包
But you have to go to a lot of work, and you have to end up using closure
围绕一个函数，以便在反复调用时记住状态。
around a function to remember the state as it gets recalled over and over again.
每次它被召回时，它都会记得它以前的状态，而且
And each time it's recalled it remembers its previous state, and
它会进行这种转变。
it does this transition.
所以这是可能的，但难度更大，而且发生了什么还不太清楚。
So it's possible but it's harder, and it's a lot less clear what's going on.
生成器是状态机的语法形式。
A generator is a syntactic form of a state machine.
虽然那不会
And while that won't
似乎这与异步编程有关。
seem like that has anything to do with asynchronous programming.
它实际上是一把神奇的钥匙，可以打开我们的一个
It's actually a magical key that will unlock one of our
我们要追求的非常重要的特征。
really important characteristics that we're going for.
所以为了达到这一点，我们想从发电机的最开始看。
So to get there, we wanna start looking right at the very beginning at generators.
我们将要看到的是，有一个新的特殊关键字叫做产量。
And what we're gonna see is that there's this new special keyword called yield.
YOURE关键字有点像老式VCR上的暂停按钮。
The yield keyword is kind of like the Pause button on an old school VCR.
你正在看一部电影，你点击暂停按钮，字面上的暂停
You're watching a movie and you click the Pause button, literally pauses
就在中帧，没有什么变化，你可以等很长时间，你想等多久就等多久。
right in mid-frame, nothing changes and you can wait as long as you want to.
然后你可以稍后过来，按下播放按钮并继续。
And then you can come along later and press the Play button and resume.
所以你可以把生成器看作是一个可暂停的函数。
So you can think of a generator as a pausable function.
一个函数，当它运行时，会遇到一个YERUND关键字，并且
A function that when it's running, would run across a yield keyword and
在那一刻，只要产量关键字出现，
at that moment, where ever the yield keyword shows up,
即使是在表达的中间。
even right in the middle of an expression.
一切都真的冻结了，它暂停了。
Everything just literally freezes, it pauses.
并且生成器进入这个暂停状态。
And the generator enters this paused state.
它将无限期地等待暂停状态，直到其他参与者
And it will wait for that pause state indefinitely until some other actor
走过来说是时候继续了，然后他们又按了播放按钮。
comes along and says it's time to resume, and they press the Play button again.
所以你可以把一个生成器想象成一个函数，它可以暂停并
So you can think about a generator as a function that can pause and
恢复，暂停和恢复，需要多少次都可以。
resume, pause and resume, as many times as necessary.
当发电机暂停时，
While a generator is paused,
在发电机的内部，所有东西都被完全阻塞了。
on the inside of the generator, everything is completely blocked.
什么都没发生。
Nothing is happening.
但这并没有阻碍整个计划。
But that's not blocking the overall program.
这是局部阻挡。
It's a localized blocking.
只在发电机内部。
Only inside of the generator.
这是一个非常关键的问题，所以即使我将要向你们展示的将
That's a really key issue, so even though what I'm about to show you will
看起来我们正在创建一种阻塞的东西，它是非常本地化的。
look like we're creating a blocking sort of a thing, it's extremely localized.
它没有阻止整个程序。
It's not blocking the entire program.
这里有一个发电机的例子。
So, here's an example of a generator.
你注意到在第1行，我们有一个小星星符号，因为我们需要
You notice on line 1, we have that little star symbol there because we need to
向其引入具有不同行为集的不同类型的函数。
introduce a different kind of function with a different set of behavior to it.
所以需要有一个引擎的语法线索。
So there needs to be a syntactic clue to the engine.
这是一种不同的东西。
This is a different sort of a thing.
所以它的函数*，这就是我们如何表示它是一个生成器。
So its function*, that's how we indicate that it's a generator.
[咳嗽]你会注意到第3行，我们在那里有产量关键字。
[COUGH] You'll notice on line 3 that we have the yield keyword there.
而放弃的关键字是暂停按钮。
And that yield keyword is the pause button.
所以就像发电机决定什么时候暂停一样。
So it's like the generator gets to decide when it wants to pause.
外面没有人可以告诉发电机什么时候暂停，所以
Nobody on the outside gets to tell the generator when to pause, so
它不能被先发制人地打断。
it cannot be pre-emptively interrupted.
这就是我们所说的合作并发，
This is what we call cooperative concurrency,
而不是先发制人的并发。
rather than preemptive concurrency.
所以先发制人意味着外面有人，
So preemptive means somebody else on the outside,
在任何给定的时刻，一些外部力量都会进来打断你。
some outside force can come in and interrupt you at any given moment.
这就是导致线程语言混乱和破坏的原因。
That's the thing that causes chaos and havoc in threaded languages.
我们没有那个。
We don't have that.
我们拥有的是生成器通过调用来决定
What we have is that the generator gets to decide by virtue of calling
YOVER关键字，何时何地以及以什么方式它想要放弃自己，
a yield keyword, when and where and in what manner it wants to yield itself,
当它想要暂停自己的时候。
when it wants to pause itself.
现在，发电机的另一个不同之处在于
Now, another thing that's different about a generator from
审美用法视角。
the esthetic usage perspective.
在第7行，当我给gen打电话时，
On line 7, when I call gen,
我调用的通常看起来像是执行一个函数。
I'm calling what normally looks like just executing a function.
我们通常希望它执行整个过程，但是
And we typically would expect for it to execute the whole thing, but
实际上，在这一点上没有一个发电机运行。
actually none of the generator runs at that point.
执行生成器实际上并不运行其任何代码，
Executing a generator does not actually run any of its code,
相反，它生成一个迭代器。
instead it produces an iterator.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：希望你们中的一些人听说过迭代器。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Some of you hopefully have heard about iterators.
迭代器是单步执行的模式化方式，
Iterators are a patterned way of stepping through,
通常单步执行一组数据。
typically stepping through a set of data.
例如，来自数据库查询的结果，
For example, the results from a database query,
您将逐个通过它们，一次只有一个结果。
you would step through them one result at a time.
你会打电话给.Next，.Next，和
You'd call .next, .next, .next, and
不断从列表中获取值结果，直到没有结果返回。
keep getting value results from a list until there were no results to come back.
这是迭代器模式。
That's the iterator pattern.
迭代器是我们能够在JavaScript中自己做的事情
And iterators are something that we've been able to do ourselves in JavaScript
很长一段时间。
for a long time.
但他们现在已经被直接作为头等公民添加到语言中。
But they've now been added directly as first class citizens to the language.
我们可以创造我们自己的，并且
We can create our own, and
我们可以使用其他机制产生的发电机。
we can use generators that are produced by other mechanisms.
在这种情况下，调用生成器会生成迭代器。
In this case, calling a generator produces an iterator.
并且在这种情况下迭代器的目的不是逐步遍历数据，
And the purpose of the iterator in this case is not to step through data,
而是从外部逐步通过我们发电机的控制。
but rather to step through the control of our generator from the outside.
同样，我们不能暂停发电机，但是
So again, we can't pause the generator, but
我们可以要求发电机运行，直到它想要暂停。
we can ask the generator to run until it wants to pause.
然后当我们调用。下一次，我们可以恢复它，然后它会再次暂停，并且
And then when we call .next again, we can resume it and then it'll pause again, and
我们可以打电话。下一步，它会继续，然后它会再次暂停。
we can call .next and it'll resume, and then it'll pause again.
所以在第7行，当我调用gen时，没有任何代码运行。
So here on line 7 when I called gen, none of the codes run.
但在8号线上，当我打第一个电话时。下一个电话，我在2号线上启动，
But on line 8 when I call the first .next call, I started up on line 2 and
我开始运行发电机。
I start running the generator.
所以我要打印出你在那里看到的Hello。
So I'm gonna print out the Hello that you see there.
当它到达第3行上的YERENCE关键字时，它将暂停并
And when it gets to the yield keyword on line 3, it's going to pause and
将控制权返回到第8行。
return control back to line 8.
然后，第8行可以立即转到第9行，并再次调用.Next并恢复它。
Line 8 could then proceed immediately to line 9 and call .next again and resume it.
这样你就可以同步通过它了。
So you can synchronously step through it.
但当然，可能会有休息，
But of course, there could be a break,
可能存在间隙，在第8行和第9行之间可能存在时间延迟。
there could be a gap, there could be a delay in time between lines 8 and 9.
在这段时间内，整个程序继续不变地运行。
And in that period of time, the overall program continues to run without change.
但不同的是，在这个生成器内部，它处于暂停状态。
But what's different is that inside of this generator, it's in this paused state.
它阻塞了，它在等待某人的到来
It's blocking, it's waiting for somebody to come along and
再次调用.Next方法以继续。
call the .next method again to resume.